Mark Kelly

Ridgefield, WA 98642 | Phone: 360.721.9342 | Email: kellymark0101@gmail.com GitHub: github.com/MarkKelly00 | Portfolio: markkelly.dev/ LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mark-kelly-9a1436160/

Full Stack Web Developer & Data Analyst

Spent the last several years building work experience that led me to where I am today: a disciplined worker with strong core values of integrity, excellence, and respect. Technology has been a passion of mine, particularly enjoying the excitement of emerging technologies. Working for the United States Air Force has been a privilege, allowing me to serve my country while growing further in a technical field and as a person giving me the skills to take anywhere. In both my academic and professional life, my professors and peers consistently praised me as proactive, diligent, and oriented. The ability to adapt quickly with teams, technologies, or individual projects and excel in solving complex problems. Proficient in Spanish.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, React, HTML/CSS, Node, Python, SQL, Express, JSON Database: MySQL, MongoDB

Other: Heroku, Git, Bash, Microsoft Office Suite

Dusingto						
Projects						
HawaiianJoe.com - No Longer A Company						
2004 – 2005						
Hired to design this website to sell custom screen printing Hawaiian T-Shirts.						
☐ Built a full webpage, designed graphics in Adobe Photoshop/Illustrator, while						
managing the OScommerce shopping cart.						
□ Tools used: HTML4, CSS, PHP, OScommerce.						
Alertify- http://alertifynow.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/MarkKelly00/Alertify						
2020 – 2020						
Interactive web app to alert emergency contact/s via one click.						
☐ Built the Alertify as a project with fellow classmates at the University of Oregon.						
Alertify works on mobile and standard web browsers to create a list of emergency contacts that						
you want to Alert in situation, this sends a text of your current location.						
□ Tools used: HTML5, Materialize CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node, MongoDB, and						
Google Maps API						
CodeLocker - https://codelocker.dev https://github.com/MarkKelly00/codeLocker						
2020– 2020						
Full-stack web app that allows developers to save their code in personalized Locker.						
 Designed an app that all developers to create an account, execute code in embedded 						
console with option to save for future referencing. This allows the ability to keep code private or						
share with others in the CodeLocker community.						
☐ Tools used: MongoDB, Express, React, Node.JS, Auth0, HTML5, TailwindCSS, and						
Javascript						

Experience

UNFI

Ridgefield, WA Reach Lift Operator/Associate 2011 – 2020

- Restocked/Replenished while taking accountability of all floor merchandise.
- Played a vital role in the transport of merchandise.
- Made sure the product is safely packaged and is placed in an orderly fashion.
- Influenced a positive workplace culture and developed team support of solutions.

United States Air Force

Malmstrom AFB, Montana Missile and Space Systems Technician (2M0X2) 2009-2011

- Serviced, maintained, and supervised actions on missiles, unmanned air vehicles (UAV), boosters, payloads, research and development (R&D) systems, environmental blast doors and valves, associated subsystems, components, and support equipment (SE).
- Operations of launches, tracks, and recovers of UAVs while maintaining related equipment. Performed acquisition and activation activities. Related DoD Occupational Subgroup: 163200.

١		-				
	KΩV	√Ac	hia	IDM	Δn	to:
	$I \setminus C \setminus V$		$1 \times 10^{\circ}$	/CIII	CII	LO.

☐ Top Secret Clearance - It's a qualification for my Air Force career received in 2009.
 Iraqi Campaign Medal/GWOTEM - After my deployment in Iraq, I was rewarded with
the Iraqi Campaign Medall in Honor of my service along with the Global War on Terrorism
Expedititionary Medal.
 Expert Marksman - While in the Air Force I received a bronze star on my Expert
Marksman ribbon to display that I am a qualified Expert on both the M16 and M9.
□ 2006-2008 YAA - Received the Youth Achievement Award for community service.
= =====================================

Education

Bootcamp Certificate in Full Stack Web Development University of Oregon – Eugene, OR

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Algorithms and Data Structures, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line, and Git.